[Bear] And, oh, oh, here he is.
[Gordon Ramsay] That's a
massive barracuda.
[Bear] Come on.
[Gordon Ramsay] Come on.
Come on, baby.
[Bear] Drop it, drop it,
drop it, drop it,
drop it, drop it, drop it.
Let him eat it.
[Gordon Ramsay] Take it.
Now he's on. He's got it.
[Bear] Come on.
[Gordon Ramsay] [bleep] Come on.
[Bear] Oh!
[Gordon Ramsay] Right now,
I'm between
mainland Florida and Cuba.
And trust me, the waters
here are so shallow,
and they're filled
with coral reefs.
Now, over the past
few centuries,
they've claimed
over 1,000 boats.
I just hope I don't
add to that list today.
I'm in the Florida Keys,
a series of 1,700
islands that extend over
100 miles out into
the Gulf of Mexico.
This area is so removed from
the mainland that locals have
their own name for it,
the Conch Republic.
I'm here to meet
Chef Paul Menta.
Now, according to my GPS,
he wanted to
meet me right here.
But honestly, it seems like
we're in the middle of nowhere.
Where is this guy?
Seriously?
[bleep] no.
That's not him.
No, surely not.
[bleep]. What the?
[bleep] hell.
You're crazy!
Standing in the middle of
the Florida Keys and all of a
sudden this bird flies over me.
What in the heck is going on?
This guy means business,
let me tell you.
He is not messing around.
Trust me, he's the real deal.
I mean, if he can show off
like that to meet me, that man,
he's got some balls,
let me tell you.
Paul!
[Paul Menta] Hey, hey.
[Gordon Ramsay] What was
that flying over me?
Can I bring it in?
[Paul Menta] Yeah, just
let it glide in, man.
It's really shallow in here.
[Gordon Ramsay] Man. Geez.
Good to see you, bud.
[Paul Menta] Good to see you.
-That was crazy.
-Yeah.
[Gordon Ramsay] Paul Menta is a
true Keys culinary connoisseur.
In his 30 years
living in the Keys,
he has served as a chef
at several of the finest
establishments in
the Conch Republic.
Co-founded three local
eateries and opened up
a sustainable fish market
and a rum distillery.
The only thing Paul hasn't
done is learn how to execute
the subtle arrival.
What a place.
[Paul Menta] Crazy, right?
The tides are crazy
like the people here.
[Gordon Ramsay] That bloody
jump was crazy.
What the hell's going
on here with the barrels?
[Paul Menta] Doing a
little bit of work, too.
Salt curing some barrels.
Bring them back to the
distillery later and
fill them up with some rum.
[Gordon Ramsay] You're
actually salting rum.
[Paul Menta] Yeah. Think about
it like we do as a chef, right?
[Gordon Ramsay] Sure.
[Paul Menta] Put salt water
in here, let that cure,
bring out all that flavor.
[Gordon Ramsay] I love that.
[Paul Menta] We got to get
them up on the beach.
We can roll these up.
-Just roll them.
-Let's get, yeah.
Let's get these
smaller ones up here.
Once I got that brine in there,
I know the wood's all opened up.
All that vanilla and all
those things are exposed
inside the wood.
And then we get the
high proof in there.
[Gordon Ramsay] Wow.
What a great technique,